# Mohsin Haider

# https://mohsinh.com/

## **OVERVIEW**

Creative and collaborative undergraduate with practical experience in design, prototyping, and mechanical development. Demonstrated ability in communicating complex topics in a clear and effective way to a broad audience.

• Design Tools: Fusion 360, Illustrator, Inkscape

• Prototyping: Laser Cutting, Waterjet, 3D Printing, CNC Milling, CAM

Programming: Python, Arduino, GitHub, Heroku, some experience with MATLAB

• Soft Skills: Communication, Problem Solving, Flexibility

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science in Engineering** 

Expected May 2022

Mechanical Engineering Intent

Pratt School of Engineering, Duke University, Durham, NC

GPA: 3.8 May 2018

High School Diploma

Ma Raleigh Charter High School, Raleigh, NC

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DesignHub, Duke University

Durham, NC

Design Engineer

Aug 2019 — Present

- Design products, mechanisms, and prototypes for DesignHub clients as a contract engineer
- Develop important client ideas into functional products through structured project management
- Currently working on a smart toilet seat (see below)

Innovation Co-Lab Studio, Duke University

Durham, NC

Co-Lab Staff

Aug 2018 — Aug 2019

- Troubleshooted, repaired, and maintained fleet of 75 3D printers in Duke University's Co-Lab Studio (Makerspace)
- Instructed students on how to operate 3D printers, water jet cutters, laser cutters, and CNC machines
- Advised wide variety of clients on best methods to utilize Co-Lab machines for their projects

### **PROJECTS** (see more on website above)

The David Lab at Duke University

Durham, NC

Project: Smart Toilet

Jun 2019 — Present

- Leading mechanical development and testing for a smart toilet biomedical device
- Designing and creating sensor mechanisms, device prototypes, automated testing rigs and validation devices
- Gaining experience in biomedical device design and regulations, patents, and mechanical design

Museum of Life and Science, Duke University (Freshman Engineering Project)

Durham, NC

#### Project: Automatic Skunk Feeder

Aug 2018 — Dec 2018

- Designed and constructed, with three other students, a feeder for small mammals in captive enclosures that dispenses food at random times in variable locations
- Initially created device for skunks but is being applied for use with chinchillas, possums, and lemurs at the museum

#### **VOLUNTEER AND LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE**

Programming Club, Raleigh Charter High School

Raleigh, NC

President and Founder

Aug 2017— May 2018

- Developed and taught lessons on J, Python, and HTML to club members with varying experience levels
- Managed a scheduling program for an annual event and facilitated a school-wide transition from J to Python

#### **RELEVANT COURSEWORK**

- Calculus I, II, and III
- Fundamental Engineering Design
- Mechanics of Solids

- Linear Algebra, Differential Equations
- Introductory Programming
- Physics: Mechanics, Electricity, Magnetism